<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-17T14:48:41-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/</id><title type="html">Dwg Creations</title><subtitle>A cache of my findings.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Working with Remote Desktop Protocol in 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/it/cmd/networking/2018/07/17/working-with-RDP-in-2018.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Working with Remote Desktop Protocol in 2018" /><published>2018-07-17T09:09:13-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-17T09:09:13-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/it/cmd/networking/2018/07/17/working-with-RDP-in-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/it/cmd/networking/2018/07/17/working-with-RDP-in-2018.html">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Remote desktop” is designed to allow remote control of a computer, with many capabilities rendered accessible in the same type of fashion as if you were physically at the workstation.
There are pros and cons to using Remote Desktop Protocol (Known as RDP, and also as RDC for Remote Desktop Connection). Much of it depends on which &lt;b&gt;form&lt;/b&gt; of remote desktop software you chose to use.
In this blog post, I will detail the options we have right now in this time, and the different past configurations we used that lead up to what we currently use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The beginning&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Windows XP and onwards, every version of Windows has included a form of RDP accessibility.
The first version, known as &lt;b&gt;“4.0 Terminal Services Client”&lt;/b&gt; was released along with “terminal services” as part of &lt;i&gt;Microsoft Windows NT 4.0 Server, Terminal Server Edition&lt;/i&gt;. The protocol was based on the &lt;b&gt;model ITU-T T.128&lt;/b&gt; example from the &lt;b&gt;T.120&lt;/b&gt; recommendation series.
The company Citrix had a &lt;i&gt;“MultiWin”&lt;/i&gt; technology which was previously used in windows 3.1 to support multiple logins. Microsoft called upon Citrix to use this technology in the design of the 4.0 model.
The DLLs used in this were still branded with Citrix, rather than Microsoft. When 5.0 came around with the release of &lt;b&gt;Windows 2000 Server&lt;/b&gt; it included many improvements to the design, including the functionality to support printing, and streamlined network bandwidth usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Evolution&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the release of Windows XP and RDC &lt;b&gt;version 5.1&lt;/b&gt;, the name of the technology was officially re-branded from &lt;i&gt;Terminal Services Client&lt;/i&gt; to &lt;i&gt;Remote Desktop Connection&lt;/i&gt; as it would be known from there onwards.
This was the first time that audio was available to be streamed through remote services, as well as 24-bit color display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Version 5.2&lt;/b&gt; coincided with the release of &lt;i&gt;Windows Server 2003&lt;/i&gt; and would be used in the future with &lt;i&gt;Windows XP Professional x64 Edition&lt;/i&gt;.
This was the first version that offered local resource mapping, session directories, and console mode connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Version 6&lt;/b&gt; was included with &lt;i&gt;Windows Vista&lt;/i&gt;. Many new quality-of-life features were added, such as multi-monitor support, large desktop support, and the much needed Network Level Authentication. This version would be included also with the &lt;i&gt;Windows XP Service Pack 2&lt;/i&gt;, as well as &lt;i&gt;Windows Server 2003 SP1/SP2&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Version 6.1&lt;/b&gt; was released alongside Windows Server 2008, which focused on printing redirection, to allow clients to have print capabilities within remote applications without the hassle of needing to install printer drivers on the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Version 7&lt;/b&gt; came out with Windows 7 and Windows Server 2008 R2. This marked the formal change from &lt;i&gt;“Terminal Services”&lt;/i&gt; to &lt;i&gt;“Remote Desktop Services&lt;/i&gt;. This update included some major changes, such as the capability to support the &lt;i&gt;Aero glass&lt;/i&gt; desktop subsystem, bidirectional audio, and multiple monitor support (at a much more reliable level than before).
However, most of these bells and whistles are only available on &lt;i&gt;Windows 7 Enterprise&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;Ultimate editions&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Version 8&lt;/b&gt;: Released alongside &lt;i&gt;Windows 8&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Windows Server 2012&lt;/i&gt; a particular focus was placed on the graphics capabilities across the protocol. Functions such as Adaptive Graphics, vGPU support, a “quality-slider” and more were key focus points on this version release. The shadow feature, which allowed a user to previously monitor an RDP session without notice, had been stripped; The aero glass feature was also done away with, as it was no longer being utilized in Windows 8 (and onwards)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Version 8.1&lt;/b&gt;: You guessed it, this was released alongside &lt;i&gt;Windows 8.1&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Windows Server 2012 R2&lt;/i&gt;. Support for shadowing was &lt;b&gt;added back by popular demand&lt;/b&gt; and many visual glitches on applications such as Microsoft Office 2013 running &lt;i&gt;RemoteApp&lt;/i&gt; were resolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Version 10&lt;/b&gt;: This is the current version as of 2018, and was released along with Windows 10. H.264/AVC compression has been introduced to improve the graphic compression. AutoSize zoom functionality has also been added, to allow the user the resize the RDP window to any size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Competition&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many different alternatives have popped up over the years. One of the most popular, known as TeamViewer, has been around nearly as long as the protocol itself. There are caveats to using any alternative in general, due to the fact that you’ll need to download third party software. One of the inherent pros to using this software is that it is already bundled with Windows.
Another hugely popular protocol known as VNC, has many different applications (TightVNC, TigerVNC, VNCConnect, etc) Virtual Network Computing protocol is outside the scope of this article, but is a notible alternative to RDP/RDC &lt;b&gt;especially if you use Linux&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terminal Services have come a long way. Now known as Remote Desktop Services, it’s one of the most used tools by IT professionals. The changes that have been made over the years have been somewhat broad, but the product we use today is very focused and useful for many different tasks.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Golliher</name></author><summary type="html">Introduction</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/jekyll/update/2018/07/17/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2018-07-17T09:09:13-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-17T09:09:13-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/jekyll/update/2018/07/17/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/jekyll/update/2018/07/17/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Maximizing laptop and mobile device battery life</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/it/laptop/battery/mobile/ios/android/2018/07/17/maximizing-laptop-mobile-battery.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Maximizing laptop and mobile device battery life" /><published>2018-07-17T09:09:13-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-17T09:09:13-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/it/laptop/battery/mobile/ios/android/2018/07/17/maximizing-laptop-mobile-battery</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/it/laptop/battery/mobile/ios/android/2018/07/17/maximizing-laptop-mobile-battery.html">&lt;h2&gt;Nickel-cadium(NiCd) vs Nickel-metal hydride (NiMH) vs Alkaline&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the longest time, Nickel-cadium batteries were used in just about anything. They contain Cadium, which is a toxic material that decays over an extremely long period of time. NiCd Batteries can charge
easier (with less sophisticated technology) and also faster than their NiMH counterpart. However, with the availability of “smart chargers” and taking into account that NiMH have a higher capacity, it’s usually better to go with NiMH.
That’s not always the case though, for example, devices that require a higher “spike” voltage such as a cordless drill, will perform better with a NiCd battery than a NiMH battery. Alkaline are one of the worst choices as they are not rechargeable. Both NiMH and NiCd are better for high-drain devices. For things like an alarm clock, and smoke detector, just throw a cheap alkaline in it. Could you imagine how silly it would be if laptops supported alkaline batteries? 
“Requires 24x AA batteries”. “Requires 32x AA batteries” No thanks!
In early portable gaming though, this was actually a thing. Take the Virtual-boy for example. It took a staggering 9 AA batteries to operate it. The GameGear took 6. This was of course before rechargeable batteries were a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Lithium Ion (LiIon)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lithium Ion are a newer type of technology that are not only smaller and lighter than their Nickel cousins, but also cost nearly three times as much to manufacture. One of the largest advantages to using Lithium Ion over the other Nickel variety is the lack of “memory effect” where a nickel battery has been recharged before it was fully discharged; the battery “remembers” the smaller capacity.
LiIon batteries are used in most all laptops, tablets, smartphones, and other newer devices. Another large advantage is that Lithium Ion has virtually no self-discharge. Meaning, you can store a lithium battery for a long time and not worry about it bottoming out. 
Again though, there is a difference in the voltages delivered. Coming back to the earlier example with the cordless drill, they would require typically 18 to 24v of power. Lithium Ion batteries that are rated 18v &lt;b&gt;have the potential to deliver&lt;/b&gt; that rated 18v, where NiCd batteries are a constant full 18v at the “rails”.
In this situation, NiCd is the winner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Maximizing laptop and mobile device battery life&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rule of thumb here is to never let the device discharge completely and let it sit discharged. This is one of the worst things you can accidently do to your battery.
Another bad thing is charging from 97% -&amp;gt; 100% over and over again. This happens a lot typically with a laptop setup that is plugged in. When the user goes to move the laptop from one room to another,
the battery percentage drops a few %, and then comes back up when the charger is reconnected. This type of charging greatly diminishes your batteries life-span.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get around this, several manufacturers have come up with software for their laptops to limit the device from being able to charge above 79%. This keeps the battery at a safer level, where it isn’t constantly hitting the ceiling and dipping down, it’s more “swimmingly” happy.
Some laptops vary and will have this option tucked away within the BIOS. Others will need their BIOS updated to even see the option. Toshiba/Lenovo include a software with their laptops that is OS-level, which has an option to limit the charging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another tip I can offer is that if you know you will be keeping the laptop plugged in for days at a time, it’s good to charge the battery to around 80%, and then remove it placing it in a drawer or cabinet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Never place your battery in the freezer, this is not only dangerous, but it really does not accomplish anything.&lt;/b&gt; Always dispose of your batteries (especially NiCd batteries) at your local recycling center.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Golliher</name></author><summary type="html">Nickel-cadium(NiCd) vs Nickel-metal hydride (NiMH) vs Alkaline For the longest time, Nickel-cadium batteries were used in just about anything. They contain Cadium, which is a toxic material that decays over an extremely long period of time. NiCd Batteries can charge easier (with less sophisticated technology) and also faster than their NiMH counterpart. However, with the availability of “smart chargers” and taking into account that NiMH have a higher capacity, it’s usually better to go with NiMH. That’s not always the case though, for example, devices that require a higher “spike” voltage such as a cordless drill, will perform better with a NiCd battery than a NiMH battery. Alkaline are one of the worst choices as they are not rechargeable. Both NiMH and NiCd are better for high-drain devices. For things like an alarm clock, and smoke detector, just throw a cheap alkaline in it. Could you imagine how silly it would be if laptops supported alkaline batteries? “Requires 24x AA batteries”. “Requires 32x AA batteries” No thanks! In early portable gaming though, this was actually a thing. Take the Virtual-boy for example. It took a staggering 9 AA batteries to operate it. The GameGear took 6. This was of course before rechargeable batteries were a big deal.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Backing up Windows 10</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/it/backup/images/2018/07/17/backing-up-windows-10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Backing up Windows 10" /><published>2018-07-17T09:09:13-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-17T09:09:13-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/it/backup/images/2018/07/17/backing-up-windows-10</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/it/backup/images/2018/07/17/backing-up-windows-10.html">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backing up Windows 10 is one of the easy routine maintenance things that can be completely automated, with a little tinkering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The new built-in Windows backup &quot;File History&quot;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you go to Settings and backup, you’ll find that the backup feature in Windows 10 is focused around File History.
This approach in some aspects can be useful, as it theoretically puts less drag on the drives since it’s backing up files based on &lt;b&gt;usage&lt;/b&gt;. Meaning, if a file is left untouched between backups, it is not redundantly backed up in the way it used to be with Windows 7’s backup-restore function.
This is pretty important if you’re using SSD drives, and/or are worried about unnecessary and redundant i/os. Some may consider it “min-maxing” and they are right in one aspect, being that drives are so cheap nowadays you shouldn’t worry about wearing them out being replaceable as they are. On the other hand, each backup-restore that you perform &lt;i&gt;without file-history&lt;/i&gt; will take considerably longer. If you backup when you’re in bed, this isn’t a problem either.
Images are also compressed and can be overall more space-friendly when you’re backing up lots of things.
Some people, including myself still opt for using the Windows 7 backup-restore feature. Below I’ll explain why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Old ways die hard&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To some it may seem archaic to do a full image type backup. But it still definitely has it’s use. One of the main things being the native functionality of it. 
An image can be applied to different computers, with different hardware. You’ll have difficulty getting around that if you rely on a file-history exclusive backup.
A good example of this happened to me recently. I had a hard drive go bad, and without a backup I grumbled about reloading Windows 10 manually. Then I remembered I have a VMware backup image of a 
Windows 10 deployment with all the software I use already installed. I booted the image up in VMWare, attached a new physical hard drive as a secondary within the VM and just did a clone copy of the VMware OS drive.
I put the hard drive in the laptop and it booted up fine, and proceeded to automatically update it’s own drivers via Windows Update. Pretty nifty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Third party software viability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I typically do not recommend any software for things that can be done by command line, but if you’re queasy about it, there are a few good options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Macrium Reflect &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrium.com/reflectfree&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt; is a pretty good free utility that you can use to make a clone like I talked about above. It has a full GUI and double-checks if you want to do things (warnings for things such as deleting system partitions, etc)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Paragon Partition Manager &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paragon-software.com/free/pm-express/&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt; useful application for doing many different partition operations like resizing. Recommended for those who get anxious at the cmd line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Acronis True Image &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acronis.com/en-us/personal/true-image-features/&quot;&gt;Link&lt;a&gt; another application like Macrium Reflect, it performs backups using full images.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Cloud backup for system images&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I didn’t cover on purpose is Cloud backups. That’s because (for home users) it’s still very unusable to use this for full image backups. The reason why is the current average Internet bandwidth for a household wouldn’t support it. For individual file backups, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com/drive&quot;&gt;Google Drive&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://onedrive.ms&quot;&gt;Microsoft Onedrive&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mega.co.nz&quot;&gt;Mega&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Golliher</name></author><summary type="html">Introduction Backing up Windows 10 is one of the easy routine maintenance things that can be completely automated, with a little tinkering.</summary></entry></feed>